Guide to the Vietnam War: Statistical Analysis and Evaluation Projects, 1968-1972
Vietnam War: Statistical Analysis and Evaluation Projects, 1968-1972
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Vietnam War: statistical analysis and evaluation projects, 1968-1972
4406
William G. Prince
.7 cubic ft.
Manuals, reports, questionnaires, correspondence, and other documents.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Documentation for various automated systems designed to provide data about the war in Vietnam.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Documentation for various automated systems designed to provide data about the war in Vietnam. Systems include Project Corona Harvest to evaluate the effectiveness of airpower in Southeast Asia; Hamlet Evaluation System (HES), a reporting system designed to gather data on the progress of the rural pacification effort; SEAPRS (Southeast Asia Province file), designed to facilitate analysis of friendly and enemy military and pacification activity at the province level; PAAS (Pacification Attitude Analysis System), an automated system to provide a means of processing and reporting the results of surveys to determine the attitudes of the Vietnamese people toward pacification, the war, and political, social, and economic development; SEER (System for Evaluating the Effectiveness of RVNAF), designed to provide quantified evaluations of Vietnamese armed forces unit combat effectiveness in performance of assigned missions; AIRSUM (Air Summary Data Base), an historical record of all offensive air activity in Southeast Asia from 1965 to 1972; and Project Corona Harvest, an Air Force project designed to evaluate the effectiveness of air power in Southeast Asia from 1954.
Documentation was compiled by Prince as part of an Analysis of Vietnamization project, conducted by the Dept. of Applied Science and Technology, Bendix Aerospace Systems Division, sponsored by the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, and completed in 1973.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Prince, William G.
Subjects:
Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975.; Combat--Statistics--Information sources.; Internal security--Vietnam.; Insurgency--Vietnam.; Military art and science--Data processing.; Military art and science--Automation.; Military assistance, American--Southeast Asia--Computer programs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIAL
Additional pamphlets and reports by William G. Prince are housed in the Echols Collection, Kroch Library, Cornell University.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Project Corona Harvest
Box 1
Series II. HES 70
Box 1
Series III. SEAPRS
Box 1
Series IV. PAAS
Box 1
Series V. SEER
Box 1
Series VI. AIRSUM
Boxes 1 and 2
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Project Corona Harvest
  System to evaluate the effectiveness of airpower in Southeast Asia, encompassing all airpower employed from 1954 to the end of the conflict (Air Force project).
  - Operating instructions, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II. HES 70
  Hamlet Evaluation System--reporting system designed to gather data on the progress of the rural pacification effort.
  Data gathering instrument--formatted, multiple choice questionnaire:
  Respondent--U.S. advisors in the field
  Sample size--Every inhabited hamlet and village in south Vietnam
  Frequency of reporting--Every hamlet and village reported each month
  - Comparison of HES 70 and PAAS (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Memo, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Appendix A--Question codes, question responses (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hamlet level HES statistics and plots by NMCSSC for village program analysis (1) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - VSSG IDX (2) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Security (3) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Econ. str. (4) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Econ. stm. (5) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - [unlabeled] (6) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Soc. ben. (7) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - GVN pol. inf. (8) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - VC pol. inf. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Prog. effort (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Misc. ques. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Series III. SEAPRS
  Southeast Asia Province file--designed to facilitate analysis of friendly and enemy military and pacification activity at the province level. Summarized data is organized by month for Province Corps, Viet Cong Military Regions, Division Tactical Areas, Special Tactical Zones, and Countrywide. Some fields use data from or indicators developed by HES.
  - Southeast Asia Province (also includes Hamlet Evaluations System Handbook), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series IV. PAAS
  Pacification Attitude Analysis System. Automated system to provide the Military Assistance Command Civil Operations and Rural Development Support, Pacification Study Group a means of processing and reporting the results of surveys to determine the attitudes of the Vietnamese people toward pacification, the War, and political, social, and economic development.
  Data gathering instrument--semi-structured informal interview:
  Respondent--Hamlet residents chosen by quota sampling techniques
  Sample size--Selected sample of hamlets in each district, sample varying in size of province
  Frequency of reporting--Data is reported monthly, each month's data representing sampling of a different group of districts
  - Functional Description for Pacification Attitude Analysis System (PAAS), Jan. 25, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Command Manual for Pacification Attitude Analysis System (PAAS), May 15, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - PAAS, May 1, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Questionnaires (Box 1, Folder 20-21)
- Series V. SEER
  System for Evaluating the Effectiveness of RVNAF Subsystems:
  AMFES (Army and Marine Forces Evaluation System)
  NFES (Naval Forces Evaluation System)
  AFES (Air Force Evaluation System)
  TFES (Territorial Forces Evaluation System)
  Objectives:
  To provide quantified objective evaluations of RVNAF unit combat effectiveness in performance of assigned missions
  To identify weaknesses and problem areas which reduce RVNAF combat and pacification effectiveness
  Includes correspondence between Thomas C. Thayer (Office of the Assistant Secretary of Defense, Systems Analysis) and Richard Cady (Bendix Aerospace Systems Division)
  - System for Evaluating the Effectiveness of the Armed Forces of the Republic of Vietnam (SEER) User's Manual, pp. 1-6, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - SEER (2), Part I, Army and Marine Forces Evaluation File, pp. 7-32, 1968-1969 Quarterly Evaluation Data (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Part II, Army and Marine Forces Evaluation File, 1968 Monthly Statistical Component, pp. 33-156 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - User's Manual, pp. 157-213 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - MACV, DIR 335-13, SEER Reports and Statistics, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - SEER User's Manual, complete (duplicate?) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Territorial Forces Evaluation System (TFES) Handbook, Nov. 1969 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Thomas Thayer to Richard Cady--correspondence, re: SEA Programs, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Series VI. AIRSUM
  Air Summary Date Base (or File). Represented an historical record of all offensive air activity in Southeast Asia from 1965 to 1972. Contains information from a number of different yet overlapping reporting systems. Data was obtained from the historical Combat Air Activities File (CACTA) and its successor since 1971, the Southeast Asia Data Base File (SEADAB).
  - AIRSUM File Documentation, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - A.I.D. (?), IndoChina Postwar Reconstruction, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Friendly and Enemy Activity Resource Profiles (by province), possibly SEAPRS (?) (Box 2, Folder 1)